

SEAN JOSEPH-PAUL MCRAE

Certified Penetration Tester & Digital Forensics Examiner SECURITY+, ACE, AME, LPI

P NEWARK, DELAWARE (302) 607-9211 ☑ MCRAESEAN97@GMAIL.COM in Linkedin.com/in/mcraesean97/ © Github.com/officialhocc



SUMMARY

Information Security Professional with expertise in risk management and the ability to identify a wide range of vulnerabilities and threats through penetration testing techniques. Capable of serving as a corporate security guru by ensuring technical security planning, testing, verification and risk analysis is in accordance with TCP/IP protocols. Capable of defining, deploying and monitoring risk management, compliance, and information security programs while functioning as a primary IT disaster recovery coordinator.



WORK EXPERIENCE

2015 – Present Licensed Private Investigator | Information Technology Manager | Special Process Server | Violent Crimes Defense Coordinator O'Rourke Investigative Associates

Managed servers, workstations, computers, laptops, routers and existing network applications. Conducted daily system health checks. Diagnosed and resolved all technical issues related to hardware and software. Ensured confidentiality of network. Managed a team of investigators to complete objectives given by attorneys relating to criminal matters. Monitored and assisted staff with work progress. Delegated work duties to staff to attain objectives. Delivered summons/subpoenas to individuals and/or businesses.

2017 – 2017 Full-Stack Web Development Apprentice

Bloc.io

Immersive project-based full-stack web development boot camp focused on front-end technologies such as JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, HTML, CSS, Ruby and Ruby on Rails.

2015 - Present Independent Security Researcher

Bugcrowd Inc.

Independent security research and vulnerability reporting on the crowd sourced bug bounty platform Bugcrowd. When (if) I have spare time, I search for exploits in well-known companies' software and help report them to make those products more secure.

2016 - Present Information Security Consultant

Independent Contractor

Conducted web vulnerability assessments to identify deficiencies within web applications. Prepared and reported all findings within a comprehensive report that explained how the vulnerabilities were identified and exploited. Provided solutions and consulting services to clients to ensure they remained compliant with their security policies, expectations and framework.



EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

2017 – 2017	Full Stack Web Development Bloc.io	2018	Security+ CompTIA
2017 – 2017	Full Stack Web Development Codeacademy	2016	Accessdata Certified Examiner (ACE) Accessdata
2015 – Present	Computer & Network Security, B.S. Wilmington University	2016	Accessdata Mobile Examiner (AME) Accessdata
2015 – 2015	Private Investigation Detective Training Institute	2017	Web Application Security Cybrary
2013 – 2015	General Studies, High school Diploma Glasgow High School	2017	HIPAA Training Cybrary
2011 – 2012	Graphic Design Delcastle Technical High School	2017	IT Security Governance Cybrary



SEAN JOSEPH-PAUL MCRAE

Certified Penetration Tester & Digital Forensics Examiner SECURITY+, ACE, AME, LPI

♥ NEWARK, DELAWARE 📞 (302) 607-9211 🖂 MCRAESEAN97@GMAIL.COM in LINKEDIN.COM/IN/MCRAESEAN97/ O GITHUB.COM/OFFICIALHOCC



TECHNICAL SUMMARY

HARDWARE/SYSTEMS

PC/Server, Routers, Firewalls, IDS, IPS DLP, Switches, Mac, Windows, Linux, Kali Linux Ubuntu, Redhat, Fedora

LANGUAGES

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, AngularJS Git, Ruby, SQL, PHP, Bash

DATABASES

Oracle, MSSQL, MYSQL, SQLite, Firebird

APPLICATIONS

FTK, WinHex, Autopsy, Paladin Forensic Suite, Zap, Burp Suite, Nmap, Dirb, Nikto, Sqlmap, Hashcat, John the Ripper, Ollydbg, Metasploit, Wireshark, Aircrack-NG, Beef, Sparta, GoBuster, Snort, OSSEC, Suricata



- Penetration Testing
- Vulnerability Assessment
- Secure Coding
- Computer Digital Forensics
- Mobile Digital Forensics
- Incident Response Procedures
- Web Application Security
- Risk Analysis
- Threat Analysis
- Risk Mitigation
- Technical/Non-Technical Communication & Report Writing
- False Positive/Negative Identification
- Root Cause Analysis

- Social Engineering
- Linux System Administration
- Windows System Administration
- Firewall Configuration
- Troubleshooting
- Project Management
- Technical Support
- Debugging
- Training
- Team Oriented
- Web Development
- Critical Thinking
- Leadership